Now let us focus on new understanding of the origin
of Chinese civilization according to some understanding
of the Neolithic age we just talked about
To sum up in fact there are two points
One is from the exotic to domestic
Another is from monism to pluralism
Let's look at the first one from the exotic to domestic
What is exotic
It means the Chinese civilization came from the west
Who brought up this idea
In last century a Swedish scholars Andersson proposed it
Andersson is a Swedish geologist
He was invited by Beiyang government
at the beginning of the last century
It was about 1915 or 1914
By the Beiyang government's invitation
He came to China to carry out geological survey
Especially for iron ore investigation
Andersson was a very professional scholar
In addition to the investigation of iron ore
he had done a lot of other jobs
Especially made a major impetus for Chinese ancient
Neolithic discovery
He found it in 1921
China's first Neolithic site
It is found in Henan Yangshao
Let us look at this picture of Yangshao
It is the excavation site of Yangshao Village in 1921
He named Culture Yangshao culture
This is the first discovery of China's
ruins of the Neolithic Culture
It can be said Andersson is one of
the founders of the pioneer
of Chinese modern archaeology
What is typical of the Yangshao culture
It¡¯s the painted pottery culture
Is the pottery, pottery culture
Andersson discovered Gansu Qijia Culture
After he found Yangshao culture sites
Qijia culture is also a kind of painted pottery culture
In that background then Mr. Andersson believed
Qijia Culture was the upper reaches of the Yangshao culture
Which means Qijia culture affected Yangshao culture
What can Qijia culture be compared with
That would be Mesopotamia pottery culture
Which was excavated more at that time
Therefore, Mr. Andersson came up a conclusion
Mesopotamia pottery culture influenced Qijia Culture
Qijia culture also influenced Yangshao culture
Such a development context and clues
It should be said that at that time we knew
Such a point of view is reasonable
That is to say the point of view is reasonable
But this exotic theory was challenged later
Where did this challenge come from
It also came from the archaeological discovery
Because later scholars actually discovered
ruins of Pei Ligang culture Which
is earlier than Qijia culture
Scholars have found that in fact
Yangshao culture affected the Qijia Culture
Instead of Qijia culture influenced of Yangshao culture
Actually to Andersson
what he saw in the direction of the culture was wrong
So that the exotic theory was impacted
Moreover, in fact painted pottery culture
is not a high-tech culture
With proper clay actually all parts of the world can produce
So this kind of painted pottery culture
Doesn¡¯t need to be explained as exotic
This is how exotic theory slowly turned into domestic theory
Now we can say that domestic theory
Is basically admitted by international scholars
It means Chinese civilization has its own origin
It has its own origin
That is what we say from exotic to domestic
Another aspect is from monism to pluralism
What is monism
Monism simply means all from central
Which means in the ancient history system
the development of our civilization
was From central China
Actually it has been challenged by scholars and impacted
Gradually from last century
Mr. Gu Jiegang's ideological trend of suspecting the ancient
in fact, broke the monism Is to break the monism
Because he overthrew the ancient legend system
That was a break of monism Since
then Mr. Fu Sinian Mr. Wang Guowei
Mr. Meng Wentong and Mr. Xu Xusheng
separately put forward their own argument
from their own view point
Mr. Wang Guowei¡¯s opinion of the difference
between the Yin and Zhou Dynasties
believes Shang and Zhou were different
with different nation and different culture
Mr. Fu Sinian also put forward the barbarian
and Huaxia East and West Also claimed the
development of eastern China and western China
Mr. Meng Wentong and Mr. Xu Xusheng
respectively proposed the development of the three series
This is from monism to pluralism development
Along with the increase of the archaeological finds
Mr. Su Bingqi's point of view we mentioned before
how did Mr. Su Bingqi describe the origin of this civilization
He is used The sky was covered with stars to describe it
There are a lot of Neolithic civilization
all around China stood on the threshold of civilization
So he used The sky was covered with stars to illustrate it
This is a typical view of pluralism
But we also need to notice a phenomenon
Although many cultures had been
standing on the threshold of civilization
and almost stepped into the civilization
But when it comes to forming a country
we know the earliest country
was still formed in central China
In other words the development of the central China
eventually leading to other areas
How to explain such a phenomenon
Yan Wenming, Professor of the Department of archaeology
called it concentric petals structure Such a point of view
The so-called concentric actually refers to Central China
Why the central China was able to form a country
To this question
so far I don't think there's a good
and satisfactory answer
we also put forward a thinking for your reference
Central China is located in the ground
Where was the junction of agricultural civilization
and nomadic civilization
In the junction there would be more conflicts and wars
War was an important reason to from countries
That may be one of the reasons
why earliest countries were formed in central China
In order to explain such a phenomenon
Mr. Yan Wenming pointed out the concentric petals structure
Later, we know Mr. Fei Xiaotong
looked at a more macro problem
and put forward the pluralism integration of multiple
He put forward the structure of pluralism integration.
He did not just focus on the origin of civilization
also concerned about the development of Chinese nation
We'll talk about it
In short we can see
The cognition of origin of Chinese civilization
went from monism to pluralism
The reference books for you
is Mr. Su Bingqi¡¯s and Mr. Yan Wenming¡¯s
works To which we can further reference
That is our new understanding
of the origin of our civilization